Mehdi Mahmud

Full-Stack Web Developer

15, Century way, B63 2TQ 👚

+44(0)7511118806 📞

mehdi.mahmud@hotmail.com 🔀

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehdi-mahmud/ in

https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/portfolio/



ABOUT ME /OBJECTIVES

Full-stack developer with a passion for coding and problem solving situated in the Birmingham area. As a skilled programmer, I can adapt to all stages of advanced programming. I am confident in my technical skills which range from coding and user interface to testing and debugging procedures. I hold a PhD in Applied Mathematics from the University of Birmingham and since 2000 I have gained experience in several different domains which include research, teaching, IT, and professional video editing. More recently, I completed an intense Full-Stack Bootcamp at the University of Birmingham, which I completed in November 2021 having obtained an overall grade of A+.



EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate | University of Birmingham May 2021-Dec 2021 **Full Stack web Development**

PhD | University of Birmingham
Oct 2015-Jul 2020 Applied Mathematics

Msc | Salahaddin University-Erbil

Oct 2007 – Jul 2009 Computational Mathematics

Bsc | Salahaddin University-Erbil
Oct 1998 – Jul 2002 General Mathematics



EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow | University of Birmingham

SEP 2019 - JUN 2021

Research project: Wall Effects on Dynamics of Cavitation Bubbles around a Dental Ultrasonic Scaler. Here, I used ABAQUS and the finite element approach to conduct a numerical study for an ultrasonic dental scaler.

Teaching Assistant | *University of Birmingham*

2015 - 2019

Teaching assistant- part time, during my PhD study in the school of Mathematics. I helped students in (Numerical Analysis, Computational Mathematics using Maple, Mathematical Biology, C++ programming and logic)

Assistant Lecturer | *University of Salahaddin-Erbil*

2009 - 2014

Full-Time Assistant lecturer at Mathematics Department / College of Science to teach (
Introduction to Cryptography, Matlab, Visual Basic, Advanced Calculus, Computational
mathematics, Numerical Analysis)

Teaching Assistant | University of Salahaddin-Erbil

2003 - 2007

Full-Time Teaching assistant at Mathematics Department to help student with (Computer programming using visual Basic, advanced calculus, Computational Mathematics using Matlab, Cryptography systems)

IT and video editor

2000 - 2014

Part-Time professional video editor in Iraqia Tv, Zagros Tv and Gulan Tv based in Erbil city. Also Helping in solving IT and technical related problems. I have used Adobe Premiere pro and Avid news cutter to edit news reports as well as tv shows.



SKILLS

Web Languages / Technologies used:

✓ HTML ✓ CSS ✓ JavaScript ✓ Express.Js ✓ Node.Js ✓ Sequelize ✓ MySQL ✓ React ✓ Tailwind ✓ Bootstraps ✓ JWT ✓ Jest ✓ MongoDb ✓ ✓ Github
Other Languages
✓ Fortran ✓ Matlab ✓ Visual Basic

Other Skills

✓ Microsoft Office ✓ Adobe Premiere ✓ 3d Software (Abaqus)



Personal Skills

I am an innovative problem solver who can work effectively in a team. As a critical thinker, I enjoy solving technical challenges and building projects from ideation to execution. I am confident in both leading a project or working as part of a team which I demonstrated during my time studying for the Bootcamp. I am also able to learn and implement new technologies. My previous work as a research fellow highlights my ability to give great attention to detail in order to effectively produce high quality work. I look forward to offering my skills as a Full Stack web developer in the future as part of a fast-paced yet quality-driven team.



Find all of my projects at: https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/portfolio/

InQuizitive

Senior Developer (Developing the BackEnd and Manage the FrontEnd React Framework)

MovieTime

Senior Developer (Developing the BackEnd and fixing the Problems in the FrontEnd)

HolidayPlanner

Developer (WebPageStyling using tailwind and Api requests)



Publications

Wang, Q., Mahmud, M., Cui, J., Smith, W.R. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Numerical investigation of bubble dynamics at a corner. *Physics of Fluids*, 32(5), p.053306.

Vyas, N., Mahmud, M., Wang, Q.X. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Imaging and Quantification of the Area of Fast-Moving Microbubbles Using a High-Speed Camera and Image Analysis. *JoVE (Journal of Visualized Experiments)*, (163), p.e61509.

Rostam K. Saeed and Mehdi H. Mahmud, Solution of a system of two-dimensional linearFredholm integral equation of the second kind by quadrature methods, *Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences*, Vol.3, No.3 (2009), 1701-1715.

Mehdi H. Mahmud and Rostam K. Saeed, Numerical Solution of System of Two-DimensionalLinear Fredholm Integral Equations of the Second Kind by Adomian Decomposition Method, *Proceeding of the 4th International scientific conference of Salahaddin University-Erbil*,October 18-20, Vol.1 of 4 (2011), 31-34.fa



RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Bubble dynamics; Modeling Cavitation
- Boundary integral method
- Numerical Modeling; Computational Fluid Dynamics.
- Abagus ; Modeling Cavitation around ultrasonic dental scaler.